<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>5. Checklists on Home</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/checklists/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 5. Checklists on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright (c) 2020-2024 Thulite</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:12:37 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/docs/checklists/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>23 Ad Elements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/docs/checklists/23-ad-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 16:12:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/docs/checklists/23-ad-elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;23 COPY ELEMENTS TO REVIEW FOR EVERY AD&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;typeface: use serif. choose typeface for greatest comprehension possible. then, second (by a long shot) what conveys the image of the company&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;first sentence: short, compelling, easy to read on to sentence #2.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;second sentence: almost as important as the first. gotta keep people moving through the first two paragraphs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;paragraph headings: headers don&amp;rsquo;t have to have anything to do with the copy or selling the product. they are just meant to break up the text to make it less intimidating so the prospect reads. a big long thing of copy looks like &amp;ldquo;hard work&amp;rdquo; esp compared to one broken up into neat little chunks with headings. use headings in the middle of columns, not beginning or end. and no two lining up between columns. really, they can have absolutely nothing to do with the copy and people won&amp;rsquo;t care . . . unlike a misspelling. outrageous headings like &amp;ldquo;scrambled eggs&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;success and good things&amp;rdquo;. it&amp;rsquo;s just to make the copy less intimidating.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;product explanation: explain complicated products in a simple way and simple products in a complex way. then, have people read it. did you explain the product sufficiently? what questions do readers have?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;new features: what makes the product new, unique or novel? what makes it different than anything else on the market?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;technical explanation: this creates authority. it makes you an expert. imagine if you knew someone that knew a lot about what you wanted to buy and they told you this thing was good. you&amp;rsquo;d buy. you can use technical language here that readers don&amp;rsquo;t understand. again, it makes you an expert. if the expert says it&amp;rsquo;s good, it must be good. be an expert in the entire universe that product lives in. explain why you chose this product at this price point.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;anticipate objections: you must raise objections. remember, in printaaq a, you have to anticipate what they&amp;rsquo;re thinking. what are there concerns? installation? it breaking? what?&#xA;a. see victoria&amp;rsquo;s secret ad p. 227&#xA;b. in the magic thermostat ad, on of the major gripes/drawbacks would be installation. can be dangerous and epxensive to hire someone else to put it in. so, they highlighted that as the first &amp;ldquo;positive&amp;rdquo; after listing the negatives.&#xA;i. when we first say the magic stat, we took one look at the name and went, &amp;ldquo;yuck.&amp;rdquo; we took one look at the plastic case and said, &amp;ldquo;how cheap looking.&amp;rdquo; and when we looked for the digital read-out, it had none. so before the salesman even showed us how it workd, we were totally turned off. A REAL LOSER. … (then into the one good thing they did like)&#xA;ii. they come back to it at the very end … &amp;ldquo;beauty is only skinn deep and a name doesn&amp;rsquo;t really mean that much. but we sure wish those guys at magic stat would have named their unit something more impressive. maybe something like twinkle temp &amp;mdash;- (a joke to show it don&amp;rsquo;t matter (the objections))_&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;resolve objections: for a batt. powered razor say, &amp;ldquo;for best performance, change the battery every six months.&amp;rdquo; for service, say how easy it is. what to do. whatever. you get it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;gender: know who you&amp;rsquo;re talking to. offend no one.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;clarity: clear, simple, short and to the point. nothing fancy. except for the technical explanation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;cliches: (advertising blah blah blah.) just don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;rhythm: vary sentence lengths. he likes to use triads.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;service: if it&amp;rsquo;s expensive or hard to return for service, you must address ease of service. five-year parts and labor unconditional warranty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;physical facts: list all the physical facts. weight, size, speed . . . all that stuff. even if you think it&amp;rsquo;s unimportant. people ask.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;trial period: always include one. unless you&amp;rsquo;re selling toilet paper. tests show the longer the trial, the less chance the product is returned and the more confident they are buying. lower time periods put pressure on the customer. if you only have a week, you&amp;rsquo;ll be thinking about if you really want it all week. if you&amp;rsquo;re unsure. you&amp;rsquo;ll return. in two months, you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable. you don&amp;rsquo;t think about returning it. because you know you can.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;price comparison: to another product. do this when yours is pricey. it demonstrates value. you must be 100% fair, accurate and honest. otherwise, you can get in trouble.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;testimonials: but only from very credible people or organizations. endorsments, in other words. can use in copy, headline or photo. or the &amp;ldquo;reverse&amp;rdquo; testimonial &amp;ldquo;a famous gold star endorses the Lanier. Our unit is endorsed by our president. You&amp;rsquo;ll save $100 as a result. (go to swipes)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;price: if it&amp;rsquo;s a good price, make it obvious in print. if it won&amp;rsquo;t sell on price (it&amp;rsquo;s expensive), underplay price but don&amp;rsquo;t hide. put it somewhere in bold or on the coupon. then, they just scan it and see it and you answer the question&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;offer summary: summarize the offer toward the end. &amp;ldquo;so here&amp;rsquo;s the deal: you send us the money like this and we&amp;rsquo;ll send you this and that.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;avoid saying too much: when editing, ask &amp;ldquo;is there a simpler way to say this?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ease of ordering: recommendation &amp;ndash; use a coupon with a dotted line. they test better. it makes it clear you can order from the ad&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;ask for the order: &amp;ldquo;I urge you to buy this at no obligation, today.&amp;rdquo; finish ad, summarize order, ask for sale. you&amp;rsquo;ve got to ask for the sale. otherwise, you&amp;rsquo;re just a good conversationalist.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Is everything I have written accurate, truthful, and believable?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
